

Edmundo Freitas

Senior Frontend Engineer

Guimarães, Portugal +351 911135895 edmundo.m.o.f@gmail.com

in

edmundo-freitas



@mundosk8

Skills

JavaScript



• • • • •

Web Development

NodeJs

● ● ● ● Git

GIL

Docker

● ● ● ● ● Agile Method

• • • •

Kubernetes

● ● ● ● MongoDB

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Languages

Portuguese



Profile

Ahov!

I'm graduated in Computer Science, and programming are in my veins since a little boy. I'm a front-end engineer, who's been working on the last couple of years with react, started with the early versions, now being more proficient using it with nextjs framework. During this journey, I tried to be updated with the new design patterns, and work with other technologies such as redux, graphql, express, nestjs, typeorm, etc. I already worked with sectors such as the supply chain. I consider myself as a person who's capable of mentoring in an easy way.

I am well-versed in software development methodologies such as Agile and Scrum. With a strong background in engineering and a deep understanding of software development principles, I have successfully delivered high-quality projects throughout my career. My technical proficiency, combined with my ability to collaborate effectively and adapt to new technologies, makes me a valuable asset to any software development team.

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer

Farfetch, Braga | March 2022

- Mentoring peers
- Plan, lead and architecture project implementations such as Design System Implementation, microfrontends and modular B2B applications.
- Explore and define strategy to adopt and integrate new technologies at the frontend stack.
- Documentation and guides definitions to onboard new developers.

Software Engineer UI

Farfetch, Braga | August 2018 - March 2022

- Develop front-end B2B applications, creating Design system foundations
- Mentoring peers

Junior Software Engineer UI

Farfetch, Porto | April 2017 - August 2018

• Develop front-end applications oriented to supply chain and curstomer service

Trainee UI Developer Plug-in Programme

Farfetch, Porto | September 2016 - April 2017

Develop front-end applications oriented to supply chain and customer service.

Software engineer .NET

Vimaponto, Guimarães | October 2015 - August 2016

- Appplication development in VB.NET, VBA and C# with Primavera ERP.
- Websites maintenance.

Education

Full stack Web Development Certification

Free Code Camp | 2015 - 2016

Bachelor Computer Sciences

University of Minho, Braga | 2011 – 2015

Graded with 18/20 points on the final project